

HASITHA PRABHATH GAMAGE

No:273/34, Isuru Uyana, Biyagama. **Tel:** +94 70 2016948 | +94 71 6305702

Skype: hasithaishere | Email: hasitha.hpmax@gmail.com



PROFILE

Talented Software Tech Lead with ICT degree, strong educational background in programming and experience using cutting-edge development tools. Articulate and professional communication skills, including formal presentations and technical documentation. Productive in both team-based and self-managed projects; dedicated to maintaining up-to-date industry knowledge and IT skills.

Knowledge and Skill Areas:

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Software Development Lifecycle
- Requirement Gathering and Analysis
- Project Teamwork and Communications
- Database Designing
- Software Testing and Troubleshooting

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Languages: Java Script, Java, PHP, C#, C++, Golang

Web Technologies:, Node JS, React, Angular JS Bootstrap 4.0, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bower, Gulp, Grunt, Flow, TypeScript, Socket.IO, WebRTC

Mobile Technologies: Windows Mobile, Jquery Mobile, Android

Methodologies: OOP, UML, Design Patterns, Parallel Programming (With

CUDA), Test Driven Development(TDD)

Databases and Data Stores: MongoDB, OrientDB, SQL(MySQL, MS SQL), Redis

Middleware: Node Red, Mule ESB, CloudMQTT, CloudAMQP

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Frameworks: Express, GraphQL, Hapi.js, Play 2(Java), Spring Boot, Codeigniter, CakePHP, Slim, Restify, Unit Testing (Mocha, Chai and Chai), UI Automation (Appium, CyprusJS, Selenium & Testcafe)

CMS: Umbraco, Ucommerce, Wordpress, Joomla

Version Controlling: Git, SVN, TFS

Tools: Jetbrains IDEs, Visual Code, Eclipse, Netbeans **Cloud Providers:** AWS web services, Heroku, Hetzner

Open-source Hardware: Arduino, ESP Components(ex - ESP8266, NodeMCU),

Raspberry Pi, NVIDIA Jetson Nano, Asus Tinker Board

EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead, XGen Group (Pvt) Ltd

November 2020 - Present



Lead fully skilled, software engineering team to build next generation fintech apps which brings current financial world to next step. In this project I always focus and contribute on following key areas.

- Drive team to migrate and rewrite existing legacy platforms for improving the scalability and robustness.
- Fully automate and maintain deployment flow using GitLab CI/CD and other industry standards tools.
- Determines operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.
- Contribute to absorption of new technologies, processes and methods.
- Responsible for the timely and quality deliveries of the assigned tasks.
- Communicating frequently across all project stakeholders to ensure project team and senior management are aware of upcoming milestones and risks/issues.
- Manage knowledge at various spectrum appropriately to avoid losing it and help newcomers to pick it up fast.
- Develop an environment to focus on customer needs.
- Ensure continual improvement in customer satisfaction, delivering higher value services and productivity.
- Work as point of contact for all project related aspects with the stakeholders.
- Mentor second-level engineering team and help them to improve their career goals.
- Accomplishes engineering and organization mission by completing related results as needed.

Used Technologies

Node JS (Express Framework), React JS (With Next JS), Redis, MongoDB, MsSQL Unit Testing – Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Istanbuljs E2E Testing – Appium, CyprusJS API Integration Testing – Mocha, Chai with Mochawesome

Infrastructure and CICD

- ECS with Fargate (Auto scalable)
- ElastiCache (Redis Service)
- SQS, RabbitMQ
- Lambda (With Serverless Framework)
- S3, Cloudinary
- AWS Image Scanning(Docker Image Vulnerability Scanner)
- GitLab CI/CD
- Cloudflare
- MongoDB Atlas,
- SonarQube

EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead, Delenta Incorporation (UK)

January 2020 - November 2020



Code and lead fully skilled, multinational software engineering team to build enterprise grade coaching platform to take coaching industry to next level. This platform support to conduct online coaching, communicating, payment handling, marketing and progress tracking. In this project I always focus and contribute on following key areas.

- Migrate legacy instance based infrastructure to containerized reliable platform for improving the scalability and robustness.
- Fully automate and maintain deployment flow using GitLab CI/CD and other industry standards tools.
- Communicating frequently across all project stakeholders to ensure project team and senior management are aware of upcoming milestones and risks/issues.
- Develop an environment to focus on customer needs.
- Ensure continual improvement in customer satisfaction, delivering higher value services and productivity.
- Accomplishes engineering and organization mission by completing related results as needed.
- Mentor second-level engineering team and help them to improve their career goals.
- Contribute to absorption of new technologies, processes and methods.

KEY PROJECTS

- Delenta Client Platforam
- Delenta Coach Platform

Used Technologies

Node JS(Express Framework), Angular JS 8, Redis, MongoDB, Docker, Elasticsearch, Firebase, UI Automation (Katalon Studio Tools)

Infrastructure and CICD

AWS Web Services

- ECS with Fargate (Auto scalable)
- ElastiCache (Redis Service)
- SQS
- Lambda
- S3 buckets
- AWS Image Scanning(Docker Image Vulnerability Scanner)
- GitLab CI/CD

FXPFRIFNCF

Tech Lead, EIGHT25MEDIA (PVT) LTD

October 2019 - January 2020



Lead and manage highly skilled software engineering and DevOps teams to build and maintain enterprise grade applications for United States based clients. I always focus and contribute on following key areas.

- Build strong work relationship with the client's product management team.
- Liaise closely with client's product manager to clearly present/discuss ideas.
- Plan and estimate for technical design, development, and deployment tasks.
- Take overall responsibility and ownership of deliverables for integrations.
- Providing technical solutions for the implementations.
- Contribute to absorption of new technologies, processes and methods.
- Responsible for the timely and quality deliveries of the assigned tasks.
- Develop an open culture to instill confidence, diversity of perspectives and knowledge sharing.
- Work as point of contact for all project related aspects with the stakeholders.
- Managing partnerships with vendors and other SMEs as needed.
- Manage knowledge at various spectrums appropriately to avoid losing it and help newcomers pick it up fast.
- Develop an environment to focus on customer needs.
- Ensure continual improvement in customer satisfaction, delivering higher value services and productivity.
- Communicating frequently across all project stakeholders to ensure project team and senior management are aware of upcoming milestones and risks/issues.
- Mentor second-level engineering team with the assistance of PM/Architect.

KEY PROJECTS

- Different.com.au
- Good Green Moving
- Loyal Pet

Used Technologies

Node JS(Express Framework), GraphQL, React, Redux, Flux, Kue, Redis, MongoDB, MySQL, AWS Web Services, Docker, Elasticsearch, Unit Testing (Mocha, Chai and Chai), UI Automation (Testcafe)

Conducted Tech Sessions

- AWS Fargate: Hands-on experience
- AWS Lambda in Real Life
- E2E Testing with TestCafe
- Introduction to IOT

Associate Tech Lead, EIGHT25MEDIA (PVT) LTD

March 2018 – October 2019



Work as an Associate Tech Lead in an international team of software engineering professionals to drive and maintain development of cloud based, distributed applications in the area of Real Estate Management. We develop highly scalable application for around 2 millions of end users with zero downtime and high performance throughput.

Mainly I focused and contributed on following key areas.

- Providing technical solutions for the implementations.
- Contribute to absorption of new technologies, processes and methods.
- Responsible for the timely and quality deliveries of the assigned tasks.
- Develop an open culture to instill confidence, diversity of perspectives and knowledge sharing.
- Work as point of contact for all project related aspects with the stakeholders.
- Managing partnerships with vendors and other SMEs as needed.
- Manage knowledge at various spectrums appropriately to avoid losing it and help newcomers pick it up fast.
- Develop an environment to focus on customer needs.
- Ensure continual improvement in customer satisfaction, delivering higher value services and productivity.
- Communicating frequently across all project stakeholders to ensure project team and senior management are aware of upcoming milestones and risks/issues.
- Mentor junior team members with the assistance of PM/Architect

PROJECT

• <u>Different.com.au</u>

Used Technologies

Node JS(Express Framework), GraphQL, React, Flux, Kue, Redis, MongoDB, MySQL, AWS Web Services, Docker, Elasticsearch, Unit Testing (Mocha, Chai and Chai), UI Automation (Testcafe)

SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER, EIGHT25MEDIA (PVT) LTD

March 2017 – March 2018



Mainly I focused and contributed on following key areas.

- API layer and PaaS integrations
- Server, Network, and Application Deployment
- Data Modeling
- Business Logics (The heart of the core application values)
- User Interfaces & User Experience.
- Play the team lead role to achieve the project level and organizational goals

PROJECT

<u>Different Project</u>

Used Technologies

Node JS(Express Frameworks), React, Flux, Kue, Redis, MySQL, Docker, Gulp, webpack

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PEARSON LANKA (PVT) LTD

August 2015 – March 2017



Work as a team member in BRIX developer team. BRIX project mainly developed self-sustainable UI components, which are used in interactive education materials. Another major role of BRIX team is, develop the authoring platform for content developers and authors.

PROJECT

BIRX Developer Team (Praxis Team)

Used Technologies

Node JS(Hapi and Express Frameworks), Play Framework (Java), Google Closure, Angular JS 1.x, React JS, MongoDB, HTML 5, CSS 3, Jquery, Bootstrap 3, Freemarker, Gulp

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, VIRTUSA (PVT) LTD

August 2014 - August 2015



Work as a team member in GTO VTAF Core developer team. VTAF is a flexible test automation framework that helps create robust and scalable test automation suites and addresses gaps in traditional test automation approach.

PROJECTS

- <u>VTAF</u> Cloud Integration Project (Based on Virtusa Speed Cloud Platform)
- VTÁM (Virtusa Test Automation Manager)

Used Technologies

Java EE, Java FX, Node JS, Anguler JS 1.x, OrientDB(NoSQL Database), MySQL, HTML 5, CSS 3, Jquery, REST Web Services, Angular Bootstrap, Bootstrap 3, GSON

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, DOMORE TECHNOLOGIES (PVT) LTD

June 2012 – January 2013 & June 2013 – December 2013

Worked as part of a multi-disciplinary team, carrying out various type of tasks as requested by the IT Manager. Had a specific brief to ensure the solutions gave for customer's precisely matched their requirements.

PROJECTS

Web and Shopping Cart Integrated Projects

http://www.brgbuildingsolutions.com

http://www.brgchemicals.com

http://www.ialconsultants.com

http://www.informationresearch.co.uk

http://www.ascendantmfg.com

Used Technologies

Umbraco CMS, uCommerce, ASP.net, MSSQL, HTML, CSS, Jquery, XSLT, SOAP Web Services

Point of Sales (POS)

– Perera Pharmacy Management System

Used Technologies

Java SE, MYSQL, iReport (Jasper Report)

- Hashini Moters POS and Warehouse Management System

Used Technologies

Java SE, MySQL, Jasper Report, Openbravo, SOAP Web Services

Call Center Solutions

- Call Center, The Ministry of Highways, Ports & Shipping (1968)

Used Technologies

Elastix, PHP, MYSQL, Web Services, 3CX/QuteCom Softphone.

ASSISTANT MANAGER, HOTEL SAJEEWYA, KURUWITA, RATNAPURA

January 2009 - May 2009

Responsible for driving all areas of the business and for leading teams to deliver results. Also in charge of monitoring and driving a range of key performance indicators within a fast paced, high volume retail environment. Also coordinate all the events and function which held in the hotel premises.

RAJARATA UNIVERSITY OF SRI LANKA, MIHINTHALE.

B. Sc. Information and Communication Technology (4 Year Degree with Second Upper Division Class).

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

The curriculum includes Parallel and Cluster Computing, Human Computer Interaction, Object Oriented Program, Advanced Computer Networks, Data Structures and Algorithms, Embedded Systems, Information Systems Security, Mobile Computing, Intelligent Systems, Database systems and etc.

Having a GPA of 3.39/4.0

SIVALI CENTRAL COLLEGE, RATNAPURA.

G.C.E. Advanced Level Examination (2007):

Biology - B | Chemistry - B | Physics - C

G.C.E. Ordinary Level Examination (2004):

Seven (7) As and Three (3) Bs

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

MOTOROLA INTERUNIVERSITY MOBILE SOFTWARE COMPETITION 2011

Motorola Solutions Sri Lanka October 2011

Our team selected for final round of this competition and we implement computer based train signaling system. Project code name is CRMS (Computerized Railway Management System).

My Contribution -

- Project Manager
- Application Developer

Used Technologies and Devices -

Motorola VC 6090 Device, Windows Mobile 6.5 SDK, C#, Ozeki SMS server, Microsoft SQL 2008 (With MS SQL CE), MySQL, Web Services, TCP Sockets (Socket Programming).

POWER MAN - POWER MANAGEMENT TOOL

November 2013

We designed and implement real-time power management tool for home users and enterprise users who want to measure or calculate power consumption and control the electronic devices remotely.

My Contribution -

- Project Manager
- Application Developer

Used Technologies and Devices -

Java, PHP (With Codeigniter framework), My SQL, HTML 5, CSS 3, Jquery, Web Services, JSON, Sailwider Power Management Tools, Raspberry PI

MODELING A DYNAMICALLY SCALABLE GRID, BASED ON MOBILE DEVICES

(Fourth Year Individual Research) February 2014

The main objective of the research is to develop low power consumption, scalable and highly efficient prototype of the grid, based on the currently available mobile devices.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Java Industrial Software Developer Course, US Technologies and Institute.
- Diploma in Computer Network Administration, Challenge IT Institute, Ratnapura Branch
- Diploma in System Analyzing, TEC-Sri Lanka, Ratnapura Branch

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Improved team working capabilities as a former assistant secretary of Association of Information and Communication Technology (ARICT), Faculty of Applied Sciences, Rajarata University of Sri Lanka.
- Champion in Wrestling(74-84kg Weight Class), Inter Faculty Sport Tournament 2010
- Runner up in Wrestling (74-84kg Weight Class), Inter Faculty Sport Tournament 2011
- Member of fresher's rugby team (Second Runners up), Fresher's Sport Tournament 2010
- Improved team working capabilities as a member of The Science Association, Computer Society, Music Team, Radio Club and Boxing Team of Sivali Central College, Ratnapura.

PERSONAL

DETAILS

NAME : Gamage Don Hasitha Prabhath Gamage

DATE OF BIRTH : 11th June 1988

GENDER : Male

CIVIL STATUS : Married

NIC NO. : 881630206V

NATIONALITY : Sri Lankan

REFERENCES

MR. DILAN WITHANACHCHI

B.Sc(Hons.) | MIT | BIT

Chief Technical Officer,

Cleato Pvt Ltd. & Easybooking (PVT) Ltd,

286 1/1,

Galle Road,

Mount Lavinia,

Sri Lanka

+94 763 303352

dilan@iquebox.com

MR. THEJAKA USGODA ARACHCHI

MSc(UOC), B.Sc(UOK)

Senior Software Architect,

Pearson Lanka Pvt. Ltd.,

Orion City,

Rigel Building, Baseline Rd,

Colombo 00900,

Sri Lanka

+94 712 667221

thejaka@gmail.com